Felix Limongi Collection of Louisiana Slavery and Civil War Materials, 1722-1872 (bulk 1802-1872): Finding Aid C0033
Manuscripts Division
- Benjamin F. Butler Correspondence, 1862 July 12-1872; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818-1893.; 1 box
  - Thomas Durant Letter to George Foster Shepley (1819-1878), 1862 December 5; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
    The second page of the letter includes another letter from Shepley to Colonel Shaffer.
  - Captain Prime Letter Certifying the Ownership of Patterson Iron Works, 1862 December 20; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - James Cosgrove Petition to the Sixth District Court of New Orleans Against Benjamin F. Butler, 1862 December 23-26; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Manuscript petition (5 pages) filed by James Cosgrove, a resident who attests to be a "loyal citizen of the United States of America" against Benjamin F. Butler, Jonas H. French, and D.N.C. Farrington for unlawful seizure of the contents of his store in New Orleans, along with a list of property seized and a summons for Butler to appear.
  - Benjamin F. Butler Letter to Thomas Durant, 1864 December 29; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Benjamin F. Butler Letter to "Henry", 1869 September 2; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Benjamin F. Butler Letter to [Durant & Hornor], 1872 May 15; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Five-page letter that appears to be to Durant & Hornor.
  - Benjamin F. Butler Letter to Mr. Hornor, 1872 June 1; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Benjamin F. Butler Letters to [Durant & Hornor], 1872 July 1-16; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Three letters that appear to be to Durant & Hornor regarding payment for legal services.
- Durant & Hornor Files on Claims Against the Union Army, 1854-1872; 1 box
  Consists of documents and correspondence regarding various claims and cases brought by civilians against the Union Army to recover property or receive damages from events occurring during the Civil War. Materials relate to cases litigated by Durant & Hornor.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1854-1858; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 47)
    4 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1861-1862; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 48)
    19 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1863; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 49)
    26 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1864; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 50)
    16 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1865; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 51)
    39 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1866; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 52)
    7 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, 1867-1872; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 53)
    5 items.
  - Claims Against the Union Army, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Miscellaneous Louisiana Documents and Letters, 1722 April 5-1867 March 11; 1 box
  Consists of additional manuscripts, correspondence, and printed material collected by Limonge, some of which have been annotated by him.
  - Charles René Bougués, "Colonie de la Louisiane journal historique", 1722 April 5; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Bound manuscript account of occurrences at Fort Louis, New Orleans, and other places in Louisiana, made by Charles René Bougués, Secrétaire du Conseil de la Louisiane. The journal also contains markings made by Felix Limongi at a later date, as well as an accompanying note about the markings.
  - General V. Beaufort, "Notes sur la Louisiane", 1802 August 19; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Manuscript document (4 pages) describing French and Spanish military forces in Louisiana and Florida, as well as notes on the population, importations, clergy, commerce, production, civil employment, clergy, and the "public spirit" in Louisiana.
  - Governor William C. C. Claiborne (1775-1817) Letter to General James Wilkinson (1757-1825), 1811 July 20; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Aux Louisianais", circa 1811-1812; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Printed broadside containing a political appeal for the election of Governor William C. C. Claiborne (1775-1817), attributed to "Un Louisianais."
  - Edmund Pendleton Gaines (1777–1849) Letter to General James Wilkinson (1757-1825), 1812 August 8; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Regarding a post offered to him.
  - Henry Clay (1777-1852) Letter to John Watkins, 1844 October 16; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Thanking Watkins for sending information about the Whig defeat in New Orleans.
  - B. M. Poyet Documents, 1862 January 18-February 22; 1 box
    Poyet was an apostolic missionary in New Orleans. The materials regard conflicts over clergy positions in Louisiana.
    - B. M. Poyet, "Correct Explanation of the Difficulty Between Rev. B. M. Poyet, Apost. Miss'ry, and V. Rev. E. Rousselon, V. G.", 1862 January 18; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 61)
      Printed leaflet.
    - B. M. Poyet, "Lettre a Monseigneur J. M. Odin, Archeveque de la Nouvelle-Orleans, A Propos de Cent Piastres D'Amende", 1862 February 22; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 62)
      Printed broadside.
    - B.M. Poyet Letter to Benjamin F. Butler, circa 1862; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Hobart Berrian, "Rules observed at the Office of the Fourth Auditor in the settlement for Claims to Balances due to deceased Seaman or Marines at the time of their death", 1863 April 24; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Printed circular.
  - General Ulysses S. Grant (1822-1885) Letter to Major General H. W. Halleck (1815-1872), 1863 September 19; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Letter sent from Vicksburg, Mississippi, several days after arriving from New Orleans discussing a letter from General William Tecumseh Sherman (1820-1891), the potential for sympathy with the Union in Louisiana, and Grant's health. There is also a note written at a later date, presumably by Felix Limongi, noting that Grant had been recently been thrown by a horse.
  - General Orders, No. 10: "An Act to provide for the more efficient government of the rebel States", 1867 March 11; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Printed leaflet from E. D. Townsend, Assistant Adjutant General, at the Headquarters of the Army circulating Act of Congress Public-No. 68. by command of General Ulysses S. Grant.
  - "A New Song to an Old Tune", undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 67)
    A printed broadside containing a ballad, which employs racist language and stereotypes, disparaging Anthony Paul Dostie (1821–1866), a dentist and civil rights advocate who was killed in the New Orleans massacre of 1866.